Benson John Lossing Collection
Benson John Lossing Collection,
1843-1917
Lossing, Benson John, 1813-1891.
1.75 linear ft.
The Benson John Lossing Collection is an assortment of correspondence, drawings, writings, and memorabilia relating to the 19th century historian, illustrator, and editor of The American Historical Review (1813-1891). Predominantly correspondence, the collection centers around Lossing's information gathering for his popularizations of American history, while it also illuminates the early publishing industry in the United States.
143254
Biographical History
Benson John Lossing (1813-1891), historian, editor, and wood-engraver, was born at Beekman, Dutchess County, N.Y., son of John Lossing, a farmer, and Miriam (Dorland) Lossing. Benson's father and mother died when he was a child, and his formal education was limited to three years at a district school.
During his apprenticeship to a watchmaker at Poughkeepsie he read a number of history books, and over a period of several years pursued an independent study. At the age of twenty-two he was made joint editor and proprietor of the Poughkeepsie Telegraph, Dutchess County's official Democratic journal; and when he became joint editor of the Poughkeepsie Casket, a literary fortnightly, he began to learn the art of engraving on wood from J. A. Adams, illustrator for this paper. He went to New York in 1838 and in 1839 began two years of editing and illustrating for J. S. Redfield's Family Magazine.
His Outline History of the Fine Arts, prepared largely during spare moments, was published in 1840 as one of Harper's Family Library. For the Pictorial Field Book of the American Revolution (1850-52) Lossing traveled more than eight thousand miles in the United States and Canada, collecting information and dashing off hasty sketches from which he afterwards made block drawings for engravings. Harper Bros. had advanced him the funds for this enterprise; the book was issued first in parts and later in two large octavo volumes.
During the thirty-five years that followed, Lossing published prolifically, and in all was either author or editor of more than forty titles. Among them were two more of the pictorial series, covering the War of 1812 and the Civil War. From 1872 to 1874 he was an able editor of the American Historical Record and Repertory of Notes and Queries. Lossing was twice married: in June 1833 to Alice Barritt; and during the year after her death, to Helen Sweet. The fact that Lossing's Pictorial Field Book of the American Revolution is still interesting to the layman and authoritatively valuable to the antiquarian would seem to make its author more than a mere popularizer of American history.
[Adapted from American Authors 1600-1900 (1938)]
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Benson John Lossing Collection comprises Correspondence-family, Correspondence-general, Drawings, Writings, and Memorabilia relating to the 19th century historian, illustrator, and editor of The American Historical Review (1813-1891). Predominantly correspondence, the collection centers around Lossing's information gathering for his popularizations of American history, while it also illuminates the early publishing industry in the United States.
Correspondence-family consists mostly of letters by Lossing to his wife Helen and includes single letters to and from Lossing's son, Edison. Arranged chronologically, the Correspondence-general consists of over 1000 incoming and outgoing letters written between 1843 and 1903, and includes those of artists (John C. Buttre, Thomas S. Cummings, T. Addison Richards, John Rogers, James Smillie, Robert W. Weir); antiquarians (Samuel G. Drake, Lyman C. Draper, John S. Fogg); authors (W. H. Bogart, Thomas Ewbank, Laura C. Holloway, Theodorus B. Myers, Caroline Frances Orne, Nathaniel Paine, Charles F. Richardson, James Riker, Edward M. Ruttenber, Prosper M. Wetmore, Andrew C. Zabriske); clergymen (Henry W. Bellows, Thomas B. Fairchild, Edward D. Neill, Samuel I. Prime, William B. Sprague); editors (Lyman Abbott, Henry M. Alden, Mary L. Booth, Henry B. Dawson, Evert A. Duyckinck, Sarah J. Hale); historians (Samuel G. Arnold, A. B. Berard, A. G. Brackett, Charles C. Jones, George H. Moore, Henry Onderdonk, Jeptha R. Simms, William Leete Stone, John W. Thornton, John F. Watson, Winslow C. Watson, William A. Whitehead); military figures (John W. De Peyster, Dennis H. Mahan, Brantz Mayer, William H. Morris, John E. Wool); physicians (John W. Francis, Samuel W. Francis, F. B. Hough, Usher Parsons); politicians (Charles S. Carter, Schuyler Colfax, Hiland Hall, A. B. Hasbrouck); and publishers (William H. Appleton, Henry C. Baird, Clarence W. Bowen, George W. Childs, Joseph W. Harper, Mason Brothers, George H. Putnam, George P. Putnam). There are also a number of letters written to Mrs. Lossing subsequent to her husband's death in 1891. In addition, Correspondence includes miscellaneous letters about Lossing, letter fragments, and envelopes. A selected index to the correspondence follows the box list.
Lossing's work as an illustrator and historian is represented by Drawings and Writings. The collection contains five pencil sketches, one watercolored, of mostly historical sites. Writings include various chapters from The Discovery of America and Side Lights of History, as well as an assortment of research material, notes, miscellaneous manuscripts, and clippings.
Memorabilia includes financial and legal documents and an Anderson Galleries auction catalog from 1917 containing Lossing manuscripts and drawings.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Illustrators; Historians; Publishing, printing and book arts; Abbott, Lyman, 1835-1922.; Alden, Henry Mills, 1836-1919.; Appleton, William Henry, 1814-1899.; Arnold, Samuel Greene, 1821-1880.; Atlee, Samuel Yorke.; Atlee, William Yorke.; Baird, Henry Carey, 1825-1912.; Bellows, Henry W. (Henry Whitney), 1814-1882.; Berard, A. B. (Augusta Blanche), 1824-1901.; Bogart, W. H. (William Henry), 1810-1888.; Booth, Mary L. (Mary Louise), 1831-1889.; Bowen, Clarence Winthrop, 1852-1935.; Brackett, Albert G. (Albert Gallatin), |d 1829-1896.; Brooks, N. C. (Nathan Covington), 1809-1898.; Buckingham, Stephen M.; Buttre, John Chester, 1821-1893.; Carter, Charles S.; Childs, George William, 1829-1894.; Colfax, Schuyler, 1823-1885.; Cummings, Thomas Seir, 1804-1894.; Dawson, Henry B. (Henry Barton), 1821-1889.; De Peyster, J. Watts (John Watts), 1821-1907.; Drake, Samuel Gardner, 1798-1875.; Draper, Lyman Copeland, 1815-1891.; Duychinck, Evert A. (Evert Augustus), 1816-1878.; Emmet, Thomas Addis, 1828-1919.; Ewbank, Thomas, 1793-1870.; Fairchild, Thomas B.; Fairlie, Frederick.; Fogg, John S. H.; Francis, John W. (John Wakefield), 1789-1861.; Francis, Samuel W. (Samuel Ward), 1835-1886.; Gourlie, John H.; Hale, Sarah Josepha Buell, 1788-1879.; Hall, Hiland, 1795-1885.; Harper, Joseph Wesley.; Hasbrouck, Abraham Bruyn, 1791-1879.; Holloway, Laura C. (Laura Carter), b. 1848.; Hough, Franklin Benjamin, 1822-1885.; Jones, Charles Colcock, 1831-1893.; Lossing, Benson John, 1813-1891 Archives.; McAllister, John A.; Mahan, D. H. (Dennis Hart), 1802-1871.; Mayer, Brantz, 1809-1879.; Moore, George Henry, 1823-1892.; Neill, Edward D. (Edward Duffield), 1823-1893.; Onderdonk, Henry, 1804-1886.; Orne, Caroline F. (Caroline Frances), 1818-1905.; Paine, Nathaniel, 1832-1917.; Parsons, Usher, 1788-1868.; Prime, Samuel Urenus, 1812-1885.; Putnam, George Haven, 1844-1930.; Putnam, George Palmer, 1814-1872.; Redfield, Justus Starr, 1810-1888.; Richards, T. Addison (Thomas Addison), 1820-1900.; Riker, James, 1822-1889.; Rogers, John, 1829-1904.; Ruttenber, Edward Manning, 1825-1907.; Saunders, Frederick, 1807-1902.; Simms, Jeptha Root, 1807-1883.; Smillie, James, 1807-1885.; Sprague, William Buell, 1795-1876.; Stevens, John Austin, 1827-1910.; Stone, William Leete, 1835-1908.; Thornton, John Wingate, 1818-1878.; Watson, John F. (John Fanning), 1779-1860.; Watson, Winslow C. (Winslow Cossoul), 1803-1884.; Weir, Robert Walter, 1803-1889.; Wetmore, Prosper Montgomery, 1798-1876.; Whitehead, William A. (William Adee), 1810-1884.; Wool, John Ellis, 1784-1869.; Harper Brothers.; Mason Brothers.; Artists United States.; Editors United States.; Historians United States.; History publishing United States.; Illustrators United States.; Publishers and publishing United States.; Correspondents.; Artists.; Editors.; Historians.; Illustrators.
Access Restrictions
Written permission must be obtained from SCRC and all relevant rights holders before publishing quotations, excerpts or images from any materials in this collection.
Inventory
- Correspondence-family
  - Benson J. Lossing/Helen Lossing (wife), 1857-1889; undated (Box 1)
  - Benson J. Lossing/Edison J. Lossing (son), 1880; 1890 (Box 1)
- Correspondence-general
  - 1843-1862, 34 folders (Box 1)
  - 1863-1874, 31 folders (Box 2)
  - 1875-1891, undated, 23 folders (Box 3)
  - 1896-1903, Letters to Mrs. Helen Lossing (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous (about Lossing) (Box 4)
  - Fragments (Box 4)
  - Envelopes (Box 4)
- Drawings (Box 4)
- Writings
  - "The Discovery of America", miscellaneous chapters - ms. (Box 4)
  - "Side Lights of History", miscellaneous chapters - ms. (Box 4)
  - Research material, notes (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 4)
  - Clippings (Box 4)
- Memorabilia
  - Financial and legal documents, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Reviews, miscellaneous printed material relating to William Wilson, whose book of poetry Lossing edited (Box 4)
  - Miscellany (Box 4)
  - Auction catalog from Anderson Galleries, Inc. of Lossing manuscripts and drawings, Jan. 29-30, 1917 (Box 4)
- Selected index to correspondence
  Abbott, Lyman
  1881 June 17
  1881 Sep. 22
  1881 Oct. 13
  1890 Nov. 25
  1898 July 20
  n.d.
  Adams, John D.
  Adams, John Q.
  1881 Feb. 12
  Akers, Charles
  1872 Apr. 09
  Akin, Lemuel T.
  1864 Dec. 05
  Alden, Henry Mills
  1873 June 10
  1873 Aug. 30
  Alden, John Berry
  1884 Feb. 27
  Aldrich, Charles
  1885 Apr. 07
  1885 Apr. 15
  Allen, Ethan A., Jr.
  1856 Apr. 02 (misc.)
  1856 Dec. 27
  Allen Co.
  1853 Feb. 03
  Alofsen, S.
  1861 July 02
  American Literary Bureau (See Carter, Charles S.)
  Andrews, C. W.
  1855 Oct. 08
  Andrews, William Loring
  1867 July 01
  Annable, George O.
  1853 Nov. 30
  Appleton, William Henry
  1882 Oct. 30
  1901 Mar. 20
  Armstrong, John
  1850 Sep. 01
  Arnold, Isaac Newton
  1877 Aug. 06
  Arnold, Samuel Greene
  1855 Jan. 22
  1855 July 24
  1859 Jan. 09
  1863 Jan.
  1875 Aug. 16
  1878 July 10
  1887 Apr. 21
  1887 Dec. 30
  1889 Jan. 10
  1889 Jan. 24
  1889 Feb. 24
  1890 Jan. 07
  Aspinwall, Col.
  1860 Feb. 03
  Atlee, Goodwin Yorke
  1870 Dec. 06
  Atlee, Samuel Yorke
  1857 July 03
  1857 Nov. 12
  1862 Jan.
  1862 Mar. 08
  1863 Sep. 14
  1864 July 07
  1864 July 15
  1865 Dec. 19
  1866 May 29
  1868 Apr. 15
  1869 Aug. 06
  1869 Aug. 13
  1869 Sep. 07
  1870 July 28
  1870 Aug. 08
  1870 Nov. 16
  1871 Nov. 17
  1873 Feb. 01
  1876 May 29
  1877 Jan. 31
  1889 Feb. 08
  1889 July 09
  1889 Nov. 09
  Atlee, William Yorke
  1863 July 28
  1864 Apr. 14
  Atwill, C.
  Austin, Benjamin W.
  1886 Oct. 30
  Avery, Samuel Putnam
  1883 Mar. 12
  Bagnall, W. R.
  1882 Dec. 06
  Baird, Henry Carey
  1852 Mar. 03
  1852 July 23
  1853 Mar. 30
  1855 Apr. 06
  1860 Feb. 16?
  Baker, N. B.
  1873 Aug. 21
  Ballou, D. W., Jr.
  1853 Feb. 01
  Balmanno, Robert
  1855 Feb. 27
  Bancroft, George
  1880 Jan. 03
  Bardwell, J. N.
  1876 Mar. 01
  Barnard, Frederick A. P.
  1882 Oct. 19
  A. S. Barnes Co.
  1886 June 04
  Barrett, Charles
  1870 May 25
  Barry, William
  1863 Apr. 15
  1863 Apr. 30
  1863 June 25
  Bartlett, John R.
  1861 Jan. 21
  Beach, W. W.
  1874 July 25
  Beal, Nathan R.
  1860 Apr. 04
  Beckman, James W.
  1853 Jan. 15
  Beers, F. L.
  1891 Jan. 08
  Belknap, William Worth
  1873 Oct. 09
  Bell, Clark
  Bell, T. S.
  Bellows, Henry Whitney
  1867 Feb. 05
  Bennett, L. G.
  1877 Dec. 28
  Benton, Joel
  1870 July 16
  Berard, Augusta Blanche
  [1855] May 14
  1863 Aug. 05
  1863 Nov. 19
  1865 Apr. 01
  1865 May 09
  1865 July 25
  1866 Dec. 03
  1866 Dec. 06
  1868 Oct. 18
  1876 July 24
  Bernard, R.
  1862 July 15
  1862 July 21
  1862 July 23
  Bill, Henry
  1865 Aug. 18
  Bill, Ledyard
  1865 Apr. 27
  1865 May 25
  Bishop, N. H.
  1877 Oct. 10
  Bissell, George Edwin
  1870 Dec. 12?
  1879 Mar. 28
  Bland, Fanny
  Boardman, Samuel Lane
  1876 Nov. 25
  Bogart, William Henry
  1853 Jan. 13 (misc.)
  1868? Mar. 21
  1883 Mar. 06
  Booth, Mary Louise
  1871 Oct. 02
  1871 Oct. 25
  1874 Dec. 26
  1878 May 13
  1879 Mar. 31
  1880 Jan. 17
  1880 June 14
  1881 Mar. 18
  1885 Sep. 22
  See also Harper and Brothers
  Bowen, Clarence Winthrop
  1883 Jun. 19
  1888 Oct. 23
  1888 Oct. 30
  Bowen, Henry C.
  1884 Feb. 11
  Bowen, John Eliot
  1885 May 28
  1889 Apr. 11
  Boynton, Edward Carlisle
  1868 Dec. 04
  1868 Dec. 08
  Brackett, Albert Gallatin
  1872 Apr. 16
  1872 July 28
  1883 Oct. 21
  Bradley, J. W.
  1862 Feb. 24
  Brady, John
  1863 Dec. 20
  Breck, Samuel
  1859 May 30
  1859 June 18
  Brooks, Nathan Covington
  1857 May 05
  1865 Oct. 25
  1888 May 10
  Browne, Daniel Jay
  1852 Oct. 26
  1857 Mar. 14
  Browne, John C.
  1864 Feb. 15
  Browning, W. G.
  1888 June 28
  George Bruce's Son and Company
  1882 Oct. 14
  Bruce, J. M.
  1880 Dec. 02
  Bryant, William Cullen
  1872 Feb. 11
  1872 Feb. 13
  Buchanan, William
  1863 July 17
  Buckingham, Stephen M.
  1869 June 07
  1884 Aug. 03
  1884 Aug. 26
  Bulmer, J. T.
  1889 Jan. 05
  Bunce, Oliver Bell
  1856 Apr. 03
  1875 July 12
  Burgess, Edward
  1872 Sep. 24
  Burnham, T. O. H. P.
  1862 Jan. 24
  Busteed, Richard
  1864 Jan. 26
  Butler, James D.
  1888 Aug. 03
  Butter, B. C.
  Butters, William J.
  1862 Jan. 07
  [1862] Mar. 05
  Buttre, John Chester
  1859 Apr. 16
  1859 Aug. 01
  1863 Apr. 18
  1867 Apr. 24
  1871 May 05
  1877 Oct. 29
  1877 Nov. 25
  1878 Aug. 30
  1879 July 09
  1879 Oct. 28
  1880 Dec. 04
  1882 Apr. 01
  1891 Apr. 20
  Byers, A. G.
  1864 May 28
  Callahan, S. T.
  1850 July 30
  Caman, E. A.
  1867 July 3
  Campbell, Charles
  1859 Jan. 18
  Carrington, Henry B.
  1876 Oct. 14
  Carter, Charles S.
  1871 Mar. 13
  1871 Oct. 12
  1872 Aug. 27
  1873 Jan. 28
  1874 Jan. 13
  Carter, Enoch
  1855 Nov. 26
  1872 Jan. 11
  Carter, Robert
  1873 June 12
  Case, O. D.
  1867 Apr. 06
  Chapin, John R.
  [1859] Apr. 18
  Charlier, Elie
  1883 Oct. 09
  Chase, J. E.
  1870 Jan. 13
  Chase, Nelson
  1873 June 23
  Cheney, T. Apoleon
  1865 Apr. 17
  1866 Sep. 20
  Chester, Joseph Lemuel
  1858 Apr. 08
  1858 Aug. 19
  Chester, J. W.
  1857 Mar. 30
  Chicago Sunday Gazette (See Chester, J. W.)
  Childs, Emery E.
  1873 Oct. 22
  Childs, George William
  1862 Sep. 26
  1863 July 06
  1864 Sep. 27
  1862 Mar. 20 (misc.)
  1862 Apr. 05 (misc.)
  See also Peabody, A. P.
  Church, Daniel
  1864 Mar. 27
  1864 Sep. 29
  Clark, Emmons
  1882 Nov. 25
  Clarke, Samuel C.
  1848 Oct. 21
  1885 May 21 (enclosure: from John Eliot Bowen 1885 May 28)
  Cleveland, Daniel
  1891 Jan. 12
  Coffin, Tristram
  1869 July 20
  1888 June 08
  1888 Nov. 29
  Cohen, Joshua J.
  1843 Feb. 26
  1855 Apr. 29
  Colfax, Schuyler
  1873 Mar. 20
  1881 Sep. 06
  Colver, Lincoln
  1887 Jan. 12
  Colyer, Vincent
  1864 June 10
  Combs, Leslie
  1871 Aug. 21
  Cook, Charles
  1850 Aug. 22
  Cook, John A.
  1862 Jul. 28
  Corwin, E. B.
  1856 Mar. 06
  Coryell, S. S.
  1870 Mar. 19
  Cowles, D. J.
  1862 July 18
  Craig, Isaac
  1872 Nov. 12
  1873 Sep. 05
  1883 Aug. 14
  Crane, W. C.
  1888 Aug. 24
  Crannell, W. W.
  1888 Mar. 10
  1889 Nov. 13
  Cruikshank, W.
  1852 June 28
  Cullum, George Washington
  1867 June 22
  Cummings, Thomas Seir
  1852 Oct. 21
  1882 Mar. 29
  1882 Nov. 26
  1885 Nov. 23
  1888 Jan. 08
  Cushing, Caleb
  1865 Feb. 14
  Cushman, Charles N.
  1855 Jan. 23
  Cuzner, Thomas
  1858 Dec. 29
  Dana, D., Jr.
  Darling, Charles William
  1888 May 15
  1888 May 17
  Darlington, William
  1859 Dec. 01
  1860 Feb. 08
  Dawson, Henry Barton
  1852 Mar. 15
  1866 July 04
  1881 Feb. 26
  n.d. (2)
  Day, Alfred
  1867 Nov. 09
  Dean, Nicholas
  1852 Mar. 31 (misc.)
  Deane, Charles
  1872 July 27
  De Lancey, Edward Floyd
  1872 Mar. 20
  Denham, Edward
  1891 July 07
  De Peyster, John Watts
  1860 July 04
  1865 Feb. 06
  1882 Dec. 04
  n.d. (enclosure: extract of Gen. Scott - Gen. Brown 1814 July 15)
  Derby, C. L.
  1857 Aug. 08
  Derby, James Cephas
  1884 Feb. 15
  De Vere, Schele
  1871 Nov. 06
  Dick, Franklin A.
  1865 Jan. 25
  Dickinson, Wharton
  1876 Aug. 29
  Dobbin, John Cochran
  1855 Nov. 16
  Dobbins, W. W.
  1863 Apr. 25
  1870 Feb. 01
  Doty, L.
  1862 Mar. 29
  1862 May 01
  Drake, Charles Daniel
  1865 Aug. 21
  Drake, Francis S.
  1870 Apr. 16
  Drake, Samuel Gardner
  1852 May 21
  1864 Apr. 25
  1870 Apr. 11
  1871 Oct. 31
  1871 Nov. 11
  Draper, John William
  1877 Apr. 24
  Draper, Lyman Copeland
  1854 May 17
  1854 May 29
  1854 June 06
  1854 June 16
  1854 Sep. 12
  1854 Oct. 18
  1854 Oct. 31
  1854 Dec. 17
  1855 May 16
  1859 Jan. 22
  1861 Mar. 23
  1869 Sep. 17
  1875 Oct. 24
  Duane, William
  1872 Apr. 04
  Dudley, Joseph H.
  1869 Feb. 01
  Durand, Asher Brown
  1882 May 14
  Durand, John
  1882 July 17
  1882 July 24
  Duyckinck, Evert Augustus
  1856 Sep. 18 (misc.)
  1867 Nov. 26
  1868 Dec. 25
  1872 Apr. 20
  Dwight, Theodore
  16 May 1880
  Dyer, Heman
  1856 Dec. 04
  Eagen, Sam W.
  1852 Apr. 01
  Earle, Alice Morse
  Earnshaw, William
  1866 July 18
  Eastlake, Abram P.
  1875 Feb. 08
  Eaton, John
  1876 Mar. 30
  Edwards, J.
  1879 Apr. 01
  Elliott, Frances
  Emmet, Thomas Addis
  1872 Sep. 25 (enclosure: copy of letter by Macy Ball Washington, mother of George Washington, 1760 July 02 to Joseph Ball)
  1874 Dec. 31
  1875 Dec. 09
  English, Earl
  1880 May 14
  1880 May 15
  1882 June 07
  Etting, Frank M.
  1866 June 08
  Evarts, William Maxwell
  1891 Apr. 06
  Everett, W. E.
  1863 Aug. 25
  Ewbank, Thomas
  1852 Oct. 04
  1853 July 03
  1854 Oct. 05
  1857 May 27
  Ewell, Benjamin S.
  1866 Sep. 24
  Fairchild, Thomas B.
  1852 Apr. 09
  1855 Apr. 26
  1855 Dec. 29
  1857 June 29
  1858 June 24
  1859 June 28
  1860 Dec. 08
  1861 Feb. 25
  1861 Sep. 14
  Fairlie, Frederick
  1857 Feb. 19
  1857 Mar. 03
  1857 Mar. 31
  1857 Apr. 08
  1857 Apr. 22
  1857 May 09
  Faxon, William
  1866 Nov. 26
  Field, Cyrus West
  1879 May 03
  Fisk, Jabor?
  1863 May 11
  1863 May 29
  Fiske, Daniel W.
  1863 Oct. 12
  Flagg, H.
  1862 June 20
  Flagler Company
  1883 Apr. 03
  Fogg, John S. H.
  1866 Mar. 17
  1874 Mar. 10
  1874 June 13 (enclosures: copies of historical docs. in Fogg's collection)
  1874 Aug. 19
  1874 Nov. 07
  1888 Sep. 05
  Folwell, William W.
  1874 July 22
  Forbes, Edwin
  1866 Dec. 13
  Force, M. F.
  1873 Nov. 18
  Forsyth, John
  1872 Mar. 18
  1877 Feb. 01
  1877 Feb. 03
  Foster, J.
  1864 Aug. 20
  Fox, P. V.
  1885 Sep. 03
  Fox, Theo. S.
  1853 Jan. 25
  Francis, John Wakefield
  1855 May 25
  1859 Aug. 09
  1855 Feb. 03
  1859 Oct. 22
  Francis, Samuel Ward
  1876 Dec. 07
  1880 July 28
  1882 Sep. 09
  1884 Mar. 21
  French, John W.
  1887 June 21
  Frost, John
  1853 Jan. 06 (misc.)
  Fuller, Samuel L.
  1857 July
  Funk, Isaac Kaufman
  1888 June 20
  Furness, Horace Howard
  1863 Jan. 14
  Gardner, Asa Bird
  1875 July 16
  Gautier, John S.
  1870 Apr. 23
  1870 Nov. 05
  1871 Feb. 15
  Gennet, C. M.
  1856 July 05
  1856 Aug. 01
  Gennet, W.
  1861 June 03
  1862 May 22
  Gilder, Jeannette Leonard and Joseph B.
  1884 Aug. 21
  Gilder, Richard Watson
  1871 May 29
  Gilley, Bradbury Poor
  1875 Mar. 31
  Gilmore, James Roberts
  1884 Jan. 20
  Gladwin, George E.
  1880 Dec. 27
  Goodman, Alfred T.
  1862 June 10
  1864 Jan. 04
  Goodman, Thomas A.
  1862 Nov. 15
  Goodrich, Cornelia G.
  H. S. Goodspeed Company
  1881 Oct. 20
  1884 Aug. 04
  Goodwin, William F.
  1860 June 18
  Goshem, A. T.
  1875 Mar. 02
  Gough, John Bartholomew
  1862 Mar. 06
  Gourlie, John H.
  1881 June 02
  1881 Sep. 14
  1882 Aug. 24
  1884 Dec. 04
  1886 Aug. 03
  1888 May
  1888 Aug. 02
  1888 Aug. 26
  n.d. (3)
  Greble, Edwin St. John
  1865 May 19
  Green, Samuel A.
  1874 May 19
  Hale, John M.
  1855 Dec. 17
  Hale, Sarah Josepha
  1851 May 19
  1857 Apr. 30
  Hall, Hiland
  1863 Apr. 17
  1863 May 06
  1867 Apr. 19
  1873 Apr. 24
  1873 May 10
  1874 Mar. 17
  1874 Apr. 02
  Hall, Thomas S.
  1863 Apr. 23
  Hamilton, A.
  Hamilton, John C.
  1858 Mar. 12
  Hamilton, Mary Morris
  1861 Feb. 24
  Hamilton, Philip
  1872 Nov. 18
  Hammett, Charles E., Jr.
  1852 July 09
  Hannah, George
  1870 Oct. 23
  1870 Nov. 01
  Harden, William
  Hardie, James A.
  1863 Aug. 18
  Harpel, Oscar H.
  1874 Sep. 29 (enclosures: 2 copies of broadside, "Prospectus For a Printer's Poems")
  Harper, Joseph Wesley Jr.
  1864 Mar. 05
  1868 Feb. 20
  1868 Feb. 29
  1868 Mar. 18
  1877 Mar. 22
  1878 Mar. 21
  1885 Mar.18
  See also Frost, John
  See also Allen, Ethan A., Jr.
  Harper and Brothers
  1857 Nov. 23
  1860 Apr. 28
  1860 Aug. 09?
  1868 July 29
  1870 Oct. 07
  1871 May 10
  1871 Oct. 07
  1872 Dec. 14
  1877 Mar. 19
  1881 Aug. 10
  1882 Oct. 20
  1896 Feb. 04
  1896 Sep. 23
  1887 June 30
  See also Booth, Mary Louise; Harper, Joseph W., Jr.
  Hart, Charles Henry
  1876 Aug. 03
  Hart, Harriette E.
  1870 Aug. 30
  Hasbrouck, Abraham Bruyn
  1862 July 16
  1877 Mar. 17
  Haviland, C. August
  1868 Sep. 02
  1876 Apr. 07
  Hawley, Charles
  1861 Aug. 29
  Hazen, William Babcock
  1879 Dec. 22
  1885 Mar. 02
  Headley, Joel Tyler
  Hepworth, George Hughes
  Herbert, Sidney
  1865 Jan. 21
  Holden, A. W.
  1852 Mar. 19
  Holloway, Laura Carter
  1869 Mar. 08
  1871 Apr. 23
  1886 Aug. 10
  Holt, Joseph
  1865 July 05
  Hough, Franklin Benjamin
  1852 July 21
  1870 Dec. 28
  1883 Apr. 09
  Howard, George W.
  1878 Sep. 05
  Hubbell, William Wheeler
  1863 May 20
  Ivison, Henry
  1882 Aug. 28
  Johnson, L. D.
  1860 May 30
  1861 Nov. 15
  Joline, Adrian Hoffman
  1887 Aug. 16 (misc.)
  Jones, Charles Colcock
  1872 Sep. 21
  1872 Nov. 06
  1874 Feb. 20
  Jones, Horatio G.
  1857 Sep. 10
  Jones, M. M.
  1875 Oct. 13
  Kelby, William
  1891 Apr. 29
  Kelly, John
  1882 Oct. 18
  Kelly, William
  1867 Mar. 08
  Kennedy, John A.
  1866 Aug. 08
  Ketchum, John Henry
  1884 Mar. 01
  Kidder, Edward
  1853 Apr. 14
  Kidder, Frederic
  Kimball, E. A. (Mrs.)
  1866 Nov. 20
  1867 Mar. 26
  King, Charles R.
  1887 July 29
  King, John
  1857 Feb. 18
  Kinney, B. H.
  1851 July 24
  1851 Oct. 27
  Kip, Leonard
  1870 Jan. 04
  1870 Jan. 06
  Kip, William F.
  1878 Sep. 11
  Kirk, Stephen Decatur
  1881 Sep. 13
  1881 Sep. 27
  1881 Oct. 10
  Kirke, Edmund (See Gilmore, James Roberts)
  Knoedler, W.
  1867 Oct. 28
  Lamb, Martha Joanna Reade Nash
  Lamberton, Benjamin Peffer
  1881 Jan. 07
  Latimer, Isaac
  1860 Oct. 4
  LeDuc, William Gates
  Lee, Herbert A.
  Lee, Mary Ann Randolph Custis
  Lewis, Edward
  1870 Nov. 27
  Lieber, Francis
  1872 Mar. 05
  1872 Mar. 06
  Lillington, Margaret H.
  Linn, John B.
  1877 Oct. 18
  Lippincott, Joshua Bertram
  1865 Aug. 09
  Littell, Eliakim
  1853 Feb. 28
  Liverman, George
  1860 Jan. 31
  Lossing, Benson J.
  1856 Apr. 27
  1857 Feb. 17
  1857 May 13
  1857 Aug. 27
  1857 Sep. 02
  1860
  1860 Jan. 04
  1860 Apr. 30
  1860 Dec. 04
  1861 Feb. 13
  1862 Mar. 27
  1862 Oct. 10
  1862 Dec. 17
  1862 July 24
  1863 June 27
  1864 Feb. 27
  1864 Oct. 06
  1865 Oct. 03
  1866 June 25
  1866 July 4 (2)
  1866 Nov. 27
  1866 Nov. 29
  1868 Feb. 21
  1868 Apr. 13
  1868 Dec. 19
  1869 Jan. 26?
  1869 July 09
  1869 Sep. 06
  1870 Sep. 25
  1871 July 01
  1871 Oct. 31 (2)
  1872 May 20
  1874 Feb. 05
  1874 Feb. 19
  1874 June 17
  1874 July 14
  1876 May 13
  1877 Feb. 26
  1878 May 13 (2)
  1878 Aug. 12
  1880 Jan. 13
  1880 June 28 (2)
  1881 Nov. 02
  1881 Dec. 26
  1882 Apr. 17